Planned Parenthood Federation of America Records (PPFA II): SERIES IX. Guttmacher,1947-70
Sophia Smith Collection
Planned Parenthood Federation of America Records (PPFA II): SERIES IX. Guttmacher
1947-70
Planned Parenthood Federation of America
371a_s9
0.5 linear feet
Sophia Smith Collection Smith College Northampton, MA
This series contains reprints of publications, most of which were authored or co-authored by Alan Guttmacher, M.D., who served as president of PPFA from 1962 until his death in 1974. This Series forms part of the PPFA II Records
This Series forms part of the PPFA II Records
This series contains reprints of publications, most of which were authored or co-authored by Alan Guttmacher, M.D., who served as president of PPFA from 1962 until his death in 1974. Files are arranged alphabetically by title.
NOTE: To view the series descriptions and contents lists, click on the series links below. Some files are quite large and may take several minutes to load, depending on your internet connection.
This collection is organized into ten series:
I. Chronological Files
II. Classified Files
Part 1
Part 2
III. Publications
IV. Subject Files
V. Affiliates
Part 1
Part 2
VI. Regions
VII. Minutes
VIII. Foreign
IX. Guttmacher
[X. Restricted]
PPFA has closed records created January 1, 1985 or later, with the exception of many published materials which are open to research. All records having to do with clinic defense and security are closed. PPFA has closed a small section of files in box 206 for fifty years. Researchers may request access to restricted materials from PPFA.
The Margaret Sanger Papers Microfilm Edition: Smith College Collection Series, edited by Esther Katz, et al., University Publications of America, 1995
Periodic additions to the collection are expected.
PPFA deposited these records in 1988. Various departments have since sent miscellaneous additions.
Best, Winfield; Guttmacher, Alan Frank, 1898-; McCormick, Katherine Dexter, 1876-1967; Rose, D. Kenneth; Sanger, Margaret, 1879-1966; Wattleton, Faye; Alan Guttmacher Institute--History; American Birth Control League--History; Abortion--Law and legislation-United States--History--Sources; Abortion services--History--Sources; Birth Control Clinical Research Bureau (New York, N.Y.)--History; Birth Control Federation of America--History; International Planned Parenthood Federation--History; Planned Parenthood Federation of America--History; Planned Parenthood-World Population (U.S.)--History; Birth control clinics--United States--History--Sources; Birth control--History--20th century--Sources; Birth control--Developing countries--History--20th century--Sources; Contraceptives--Research--History; Hygiene, Sexual--History--20th century; Human reproduction--Political aspects; Population policy--History--20th century; Reproductive health--Statistics; Sex instruction--History; Women--Health and hygiene--United States--20th century; Women's health services--United States--20th century
This Series forms part of the PPFA II Records
See also the PPFA I Records.
Related material can be found in the Margaret Sanger Papers, Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College, and at the Library of Congess.
- SERIES IX. GUTTMACHER
  - Publications
    - Abortion 1970 (Box 101, Folder 25)
    - Annotated List of Published Reports, Clinical Trials with Contraceptives 1959 (Box 101, Folder 26)
    - Artifizielle Insemination 1969 (Box 101, Folder 27)
    - Biographical Notes on Same Famous Conjoined Twins 1967 (Box 101, Folder 28)
    - Bootlegging Bodies 1955 (Box 101, Folder 29)
    - Caesarean Section in Twin Pregnancy 1962 (Box 101, Folder 30)
    - Compound and Complex, Presentation Assoc. with Plural Births 1962 (Box 101, Folder 31)
    - Concentrated Oxytocin Solution for Therapeutic Interruption of Miotrimester Pregnancy 1962 (Box 101, Folder 32)
    - Contraception Control: Its Implications for the Individual and World 1961 (Box 101, Folder 33)
    - Conception Control and the Medical Profession 1947 (Box 101, Folder 34)
    - Contraception 1968 (Box 101, Folder 35)
    - The Contraception Problem 1967 (Box 101, Folder 36)
    - A Critical Study of the Efficacy of Jelly as a Contraceptive 1952 (Box 101, Folder 37)
    - Medical Aspects of Human Sexuality 1968 (Box 101, Folder 38)
    - Early Attitudes Towards Infertility 1953 (Box 101, Folder 39)
    - Effectiveness of Preceptin 1954 (Box 101, Folder 40)
    - Factors Affecting Normal Expectancy of Conception 1956 (Box 101, Folder 41)
    - Factors in Decline in Incidence and Severity, undated (Box 101, Folder 42)
    - Family Planning, A Challenge to Health Workers of Every Nation 1969 (Box 101, Folder 43)
    - Family Planning, The Needs and Methods 1958 (Box 101, Folder 44)
    - The First Five Years, Obstetric Report of the Mt. Sinai Hospital, N.Y. 1952 (Box 101, Folder 45)
    - Fertility of Man 1958 (Box 101, Folder 46)
    - Fetal Electrocardiography 1958 (Box 101, Folder 47)
    - The Fetus of Multiple Gestations (Box 101, Folder 48)